GARY **SHEN**

email: gshen7@uwo.ca | in: linkedin.com/in/gshen7 | C: 226-700-3927 H: 519-679-4009

Summary of Qualifications

Experience: Relevant work experience as a research assistant along with many years of in leadership roles for self-

guided projects for clubs and science fair competitions

Technical Skills: Working Knowledge of: C++, Java, Android SDK, Excel, Matlab, Git, Weka, AutoCAD, HTML

Basic Understanding of: C, Arduino, Zigbee, RFID, Machine Learning, CSS, REST, JSON

Personal Skills: Creative problem solver able to learn new concepts quickly who welcomes challenging problems

and is able to work effectively individually or in a team environment

Education

Western University | 2015-2020 Computer Engineering and Honours **Business Administration Dual Degree**

Dean's Honor List 2016 3.99 GPA | 94% Weighted Average

Publications

Mitigating Sensor Differences for Phonebased Human Activity Recognition | 2016 Yin, X., Shen, G., Wang, X. and Shen, W. IEEE SMC 2016

Awards

NSERC USRA | 2016

Awarded 1 of 5 faculty undergraduate student research awards by the National Sciences and Engineering Research Council.

Top First Year Design Project | 2016

Course project was recognized as one of the top 10 out of over 100 first year engineering design projects.

National President's Scholarship | 2015

Awarded by Western University to recognize allround excellence and achievement in extracurricular activities and academics

Loran Scholar Program Semifinalist | 2015

Awarded to exceptional young Canadians who demonstrate character, service and leadership.

Canada Wide Science Fair | 2011-2015

CWSF Finalist in 2011, 2012, 2013 and 2015. Awarded 4 Bronze Excellence awards and the Resource Challenge award

Other Employment

Delta London Armouries | 2015-Present

Restaurant Porter and Server

London Referees Group | 2012-2016

Hockey Referee

Nor'West Soccer Club | 2012-2015

Soccer Referee

City of London | 2012-2013

Skating Instructor

Engineering Experience

Western University | November 2015-August 2016 Research Assistant and NSERC USRA Fellow

Worked on several research projects in an electrical and computer engineering lab. Projects included:

- -Exploring WiFI signal strength based indoor locationing techniques. I created RESTful web service and Android apps to exhibit and test a propagation-based and fingerprint-based system.
- -Developed Android activity recognition app and researched mitigation procedures for sensor difference effects. I wrote MatLab scripts and implemented Weka machine learning tool for data collection, classification, analysis and decision making to increase activity recognition accuracy from 76% to

Terzan Tech | November 2012-August 2015 Co-Founder and Developer

Developed assistive technologies for independent senior living. Focused on hardware interfaces for these technologies.

Additional Projects

Bed Monitoring System | 2015

Created a machine-learning based bed monitoring system to recognize bed-related activities and sleep patterns.

Children's Education App | 2015

Developed an app consisting of education focused mini games for children aged 5-10.

Fall Detection App | 2014

Wrote code for an Android app that uses smartphone accelerometer and gyroscope data to detect falls.

Keyboard Controllable Car | 2013

Built and wrote code in C for a small controllable car.

RFID Based Object Locator | 2012

Wrote code in java to detect objects with passive RFID tags.

Volunteer Causes

Heart 4 Heart Charity London Chapter | 2015-Present

Vice President of Finance

Thames Valley Science and Engineering Fair | 2015-Present

Judge and Sponsorship Team Member

Western Student Research Conference | 2015-2016

Engineering Faculty Representative

IEEE CSCWD 2013 Conference | 2013

Registration Volunteer